谢谢你的美味晚餐  不客气
So,Thanks for the delicious dinner. You're welcome for a delicious dinner.
你们在看什么
Hey,What are you guys looking at?
罗斯和宇宙无敌第一美女
Ross and the most beautiful girl in the world.
对  到爸爸这儿来
Yeah, come to Papa!
我知道
I know!
这实在不像我说的话
Probably the only time I'll say this...
但是你们注意到她的屁股了吗
...but did you see the ass on her?
你从哪儿  什么时候
What did you? When did you?
你是怎么  怎么把这样的姑娘搞到手的
How did you? How did you get a girl like that?
她是谁  车展模特  有氧舞蹈教练什么的
Yeah, so what is she, like a... like a spokesmodel, or an aerobics instructor, what?
实际上  她是古生物学博士候选人
Actually, she's a paleontology doctoral candidate...
专攻新生代
...specializing in the Cenozoic Era.
不过那是最简单的时代
Okay, But that's, like, the easiest era.
我在馆里见过她  但我一直考虑  嗯哼
I've seen her at work, but I always figured. ah-huh?
总之我做饭给她吃
But, uh, I made her dinner.
我们聊得很愉快  明天还要见面
We had a great time. And we're going out again tomorrow.
也许她跟朋友打赌  看谁能钓到最怪的怪胎
Well maybe she and her friends are just having a contest to see who can bring home the biggest geek.
我无所谓  祝她胜利
Fine by me. Hope she wins.
《老友记》  第四季  第06集  "灰"姑娘
Friends S04E06  The one with the dirty girl
（主演：詹妮弗·安妮斯顿）
（主演：柯特妮·考克斯）
（主演：丽莎·库卓）
（主演：马特·勒布朗）
（主演：马修·派瑞）
（主演：大卫·修蒙）
嘿
Hey!
你们有包装纸吗
You guys have any wrapping paper?
要包我的生日礼物么
Oo! Is it for my birthday present?
菲比  你的生日好象在一个月以前
Phebes, it was your birthday, like, months ago.
对  但你说订了特别的东西  还没送来
Yeah, but remember you said you ordered something special, and it just hasn't come yet?
好的  我有接到过电话
Well, I have a call in about that.
制片: 塔德史帝文斯
实际上  这是给凯西的生日礼物  是她最喜欢的书的早期版本
Actually, this is for Kathy's birthday. It's an early edition of her favorite book.
是《天鹅绒兔宝宝》
Oh! The Velveteen Rabbit!
天哪  当男孩的爱让他变成真兔子…
Oh my God, When the boy's love makes the rabbit real...
好  别摸了  你的手指有油污
Okay, but don't touch it, because your fingers have destructive oils.
那你最好别靠近罗斯的头发
Huh. Well, then you'd better keep it away from Ross's hair.
这应该很珍贵  你是怎么找到的
So this is pretty rare. How did you get that?
哦  没什么  我只是跑了几家书店  问了几个书商
Oh, it wasn't a big deal. I just went to a couple of bookstores, talked to a couple of dealers.
联络了几个作者的孙子
called a couple of the author's grandchildren.
真是太感人了
Oh, honey, that's so sweet.
这是完全宣告了 "室友的马子  我在暗恋你"
Yeah, and what a great way to say, "I secretly love you, roommate's girlfriend."
哪会啊…
It doesn't say that.
会吗
Does it?
你自己看嘛  你送的礼物意味深长又价值不菲
How do you think it's gonna look when you get her something incredibly meaningful and expensive
而她的男朋友乔伊  却送她一个柳橙
and her boyfriend Joey gives her an orange?
好  我只是确认一下  乔伊会送她更好的东西
Okay, all right, I'll just uh, make sure that uh, Joey gets her something really great.
要比那本书还好
It's gotta be better than that book.
像十字弓
Ooh! Like a crossbow!
对  我再次说声  抱歉
Yeah, Once again, I am sorry.
谢谢  再见
Thank you. Bye.
我推掉了一个60人的葬礼外烩
I just had to turn down a job catering a funeral for sixty people.
天哪  出什么事了死那么多人
Oh, my God! What happened?
是60个客人
Sixty guests.
那么  为什么推掉呢
So, uh, why did you have to turn it down?
我没有钱  也没有设备
Because I don't have the money or the equipment...
在这么短的时间里准备这么多的东西  我是说  这不可能
...to handle something that big on such short notice. I mean there's no way.
怎么能全都否定呢
Wow, what is with all the negativity?
你听起来象是"摩妮不可"  而不是"摩妮可"
You sound like "Moni-can't," not "Moni-can"!
摩妮 "卡"
Moni-ca.
你看啊  你做承包宴会都3年多了
Look, you know, you have been playing around with this catering thing for over three years.
你到底想不想成为宴会承包商  我不知道
Do you want to be a caterer or not? I don't know.
就是这样  精神起来
There you go! That's the spirit!
如果你现在需要钱  我借你  你就立刻接吧
Okay! Now, if you need money, I will lend you money, but just get moving!
真的  我需要5百元来采购全部食物  设备和原料
Really? Cause I'd need like $500 for all the food and the supplies and stuff.
好  值得一做  你也失业几个月了
Okay! It's worth it, if it'll get you moving. You haven't worked in months!
是啊  你不也没工作呀
Well, you're not working either.
是啊  但是我可以放债
Yes, but I'm doing this.
太好了  谢谢
Yeah, that'd be great! Thank you!
嘿  嘿
Hey! Hey!
把你家的钥匙借给我
Can I borrow the keys to your apartment?
为什么
Why?
你可以在这尿啊
You can pee here.
也对  不好意思
haha.. yes I can, of course. Excuse me.
没问题  反正鸭子也常用我们的洗手间
It's okay. The duck's using our bathroom anyway.
嗨  乔伊  你要送凯茜什么生日礼物
Hey Joe! What are you getting Kathy for her birthday?
我们刚约会了几个星期  你真认为我应该送她东西
We've only been going out for a couple of weeks, do you think I gotta get her something?
要啊
Yeah!
不但要送  还要送好的
Yes, you have to get her something, and it should be something really nice.
有了  不是1小时 "与乔伊做爱"的
Oh, I know... And not one of your coupons...
猛男体验券
...for an hour of "Joey Love."
哦  填字游戏  要我帮忙吗
Ooh! A crossword! Can I help?
不
No!
对不起  亲爱的  上个星期我就只差3个答案了
I'm sorry, honey, it's just that last week I got all but three answers ...
我很想独力完成一次
...and I really want to finish a whole one without any help.
好
Fine.
那你也不能帮我研发新的世界语了
But you can't help me develop my new universal language.
嘿  怎么样
Hey! How'd it go?
天哪  这个葬礼太棒了
Oh, my God! It was the best funeral ever!
人人都说食物好吃  而且你猜怎么着
I mean, everyone loved the food, and guess what?
我接了明天的另一场葬礼
I even got another funeral for tomorrow
是今天的死者的死党
The dead guy from today's best friend.
我是说  我看上去象是职业葬礼承办商了
I mean, It's like I am the official caterer for that accident.
莫  我真替你高兴
Mon, I'm so happy for you!
谢了  看看我的新设备
Thanks. Like, check out my new catering stuff.
看看这个  我是个煎蛋卷站
Look at this! I'm an omelet station!
要煎蛋卷吗  按秩序来
Omelet? Made to order? Ha!
我也点一份  还有我的钱
I'll have one, please. Plus my money.
哦  好的  我觉得你不是立刻需要它
Oh. Well, I didn't realize that you needed it back right away.
我是说  你叫我当个宴会承包商  我就去了  我也做了
I mean, you told me to go and be a caterer. So I went. I beed.
我把钱都花掉了  买了这些
I... I used it to buy all this stuff.
你看  我已经找到了明天的工作  到时就能还你
But look--I've got another job tomorrow, so I'll pay you back with the money I make from that.
好  抱歉刚才一副银行嘴脸
Oh. Okay. Oo, sorry I acted like a bank.
你要进来吗
Um, would you like to come in?
直立人是用木器打猎吗
Did homo-erectus hunt with wooden tools?
最新证据显示是的
According to recent findings.
蜜琪  过来  蜜琪  过来
Here, Mitzi! Here, Mitzi!
蜜琪是
Uh, Mitzi is?
我的仓鼠
My hamster.
但愿他没事  我有段时间没看到她了
I hope she's okay. I haven't seen her in a while.
请坐
Have a seat.
"坐哪里"
"Where?"
对了  你…
Uh, oh! Do you, uh...?
你有肉桂水果烤吐司吗
Do you have any, um, Cinnamon Fruit Toasties?
什么  好的  我有
What? Well, I do.
为什么不去我那儿  我们点几根蜡烛
Why don't we go back to my place, light a couple of candles,...
开一盒肉桂水果烤吐司  嗯
...break open a box of Cinnamon Fruit Toasties, uh...
我宁可不去  哦  为什么不
I'd rather not. Oh, yeah? Why not?
好的  你别太在意
Okay, um... Don't take this the wrong way...
但是你家里有一股怪味
...but your place kinda has a weird smell.
哦  东西都装上车了  对  钱拿到了吗
Oh, is everything in the car? Yes. Did you settle the bill?
还没  我最讨厌要钱了
No. I hate this part.
哦  看看我们差点还忘了什么
Oh, look what we almost left.
不  不是我的
No, that's not mine.
哦  好吧  看看我们差点拿了什么
Oh, all right. Oh! Look what we almost took!
对不起  柏卡特太太
Excuse me, Ms. Burkart?
厨房都收拾好了
Well, we're all cleaned up in the kitchen.
很好  谢谢你
Oh. Good. Thank you.
啊  哦
Um, ahem...
还有一件小事…
Um, and, well there's the.. the the small matter of...
什么事  就是…
Dear? Just the matter of ...
费用的事
...payment.
钱都是杰克在管
Jack used to handle the finances.
你知道我们应该去干什么
You know what we should all do?
去看歌舞剧
Go see a musical.
当然
Sure.
你知道应该看哪一部
And you know which one we should see?
1996年东尼奖得奖作品
The 1996 Tony Award winner.
你知道它的名字吗
Do you happen to know the name of that one?
不晓得  格雷斯
I don't know, um, Grease?
不是
No.
伦特
Rent?
对  伦特
Yes! Rent!
好  那么你打算什么时候去
Okay, so when do you want to go?
什么  对不起  我不行  我很忙
What? Oh, I'm sorry, I can't, I'm busy.
嘿
Hey...
天哪  给女孩买礼物可真累啊
Man, it is so hard to shop for girls. Ugh!
的确  很难  尤其是去马克斯商店
Yes, it is, at Office Max!
你给她买了什么
What did you get her?
一支笔
A pen.
这是二合一礼物   是笔  也是时钟
It's two gifts in one. It's a pen that's also a clock. Huh?
你不能送这个  为什么
Ha, ha. You can't give her that. Why not?
她不是11岁小孩了
Because she's not eleven!
这也不是光明节结束前第七夜
And it's not the seventh night of Chanukah.
好的  亲爱的  他的意思是  这个礼物虽然好
Okay, honey, what he means by that, is ...while this is a very nice gift...
却不太适合送给女朋友
...maybe it's just not something a boyfriend gives?
当然  适合
Sure, it is.
她上班要用到笔
She needs a pen for work.
写到一半转过来一看  "哇  该去跟乔伊约会了"
She's writing. She turns it over. "Whoa! It's time for my date with Joey!"
好  你送安琪拉.德尔维琪什么生日礼物
All right, look, look. What did... what did you get for Angela Delveccio for her birthday?
我们约会的那段时间没碰上生日
She didn't have a birthday while we were going out.
3年没有生日
For three years?
太晚了  而且我还要试镜
Look, it's too late, and I got an audition.
我不能再逛商店了  我...
I can't shop anymore! I...
好  我出去给她买件礼物  好吗
All right. I will go out and I will try to find something for her, okay?
谢了
Thanks, man.
你能不能顺便买张卡片给她
And oh, while you're at it, could you get her a card?
要不要我顺便写一首小诗
Would you like me to write her a little poem as well?
或是买张印了诗的卡片
Or just get a card that has a poem already in it.
但是  莫尼  你拿了我们的钱  哦  菲比  她不停的哭
But Mon, you have to get our money! Oh, Phoebe, she couldn't stop crying!
从厚镜片里看  眼泪珠特别的大
With those thick glasses, her tears looked giant.
我知道  这很难
I know, it's tough.
你知道我妈一下葬   我做的第一件事是什么
You know what the first thing I did after my mom's funeral was?
什么  付钱给承包宴会的人
What? Pay the caterer!
对啊  我在工作中也常碰到这种事
Look, I've had a lot of jobs, okay,
有些人总是想赖帐
and there are some people who just always try to get out of paying.
比如说  不是 "按摩时间不够长"
It's either, you know, "That massage wasn't long enough"...
就是 "我不认可这些歌"
...or, "I don't recognize any of those songs,"
要么 "这些宽边帽不怎么大  坏心眼的小姑娘"
...or, you know, "these sombreros aren't big enough. Bad little white girl!"
嗯
Okay.
好吧  那么你认为这是她在装
Okay. So what do you.... you think she's faking?
是的  你拿出帐单前她根本没哭
Well, it seems like there weren't any tears 'til you showed her the bill.
菲比  她的声音真的让我难受
Phoebe, she sounded pretty upset to me.
You're a grand old flag
You're a high-flying flag And forever in peace may you wave
她现在看上去似乎没事了
She seems fine now.
那么  你真的就走了  她家就真的那么脏
So you just left? Her place was really that bad?
你知道  下班回家会把夹克扔到椅子上
You know how you throw your jacket on a chair at the end of the day?
就象这样  在她家是扔到一堆垃圾上
Well, like that, only instead of a chair, it's a pile of garbage.
那也不是夹克  是一堆垃圾
And instead of a jacket, it's a pile of garbage.
也不是下班回家   简直是世界末日
And instead of the end of the day, it's the end of time...
幸存的只有垃圾
...and garbage is all that has survived.
拿去  谢了
Here. Wow. Thanks.
然后呢
So, uh, what happened?
哪有然后  我逃之天夭
What do you mean? Nothing happened! I had to get out of there.
好  下次  你就带她去你家
All right, so... next time, you take her to your place.
不  我试过了  她说我家有怪味
No, I tried that. She says it has a weird smell.
什么怪味  不清楚  香皂味
What kind of smell? I don't know. Soap?
好  听着  你喜欢她  对么  对
All right, listen, Ross... you like this girl, right? Yeah.
你想再跟她见面  对么
You wanna see her again, right?
那你就得在垃圾里跟她做
So you're gonna have to do it in the mess!
好吧   你说得对
Yeah, okay. You're right.
我是说  稍微乱一点  谁又在乎一点脏东西
I mean, uh, who... who cares about a little sloppiness?
其实蛮可爱的  真的  那就好
It's, uh... it's endearing, really. All right!
现在就去找这头漂亮的猪
Now you go get that beautiful pig!
好  我花了一下午替凯西找了一件
Okay, all right. I just spent the entire afternoon looking for a present...
比这只兔子好的礼物
...for Kathy that would be better than the rabbit.
找到了吗
Any luck?
有  我找到一家店  叫"送给凯西的隐形礼物"
Oh, yeah. Yeah, I found this great place called "Invisible things for Kathy."
你能不能帮我一把
Can you give me a hand with all this stuff?
好  这样  你为什么不退掉这本书  让乔伊送她那支时钟笔
All right, look. Why don't you just return the book, let Joey give her the clock pen...
你送个更差的东西  比如…
...and you get her something worse than that...
一支普通的笔
...like a regular pen.
她真的会喜欢这个  你知道
She's really going to love this, you know?
重要的是把这个送给她
The bottom line is I want her to have it...
即使她不知道是谁送的
...even if I don't get to be the one who gives it to her.
啊  亲爱的  好感人啊
Aw, honey, that's so sweet.
你不觉得很可悲吗
Yeah? You don't think it's just pathetic?
是 "可悲"
Oh, "pathetic"!
我十分钟前遇见了凯茜  我到处找你
I'm meeting Kathy in ten minutes! I've been looking all over for you!
在哪里找  家里啦  大厅啦
Where? Our place. The hall.I...
我给她买了礼物
I got something for her.
是一本书
It's a book.
书
A book?
是书也是保险盒
Is it a book that's also a safe?
它就是一本书
No, it's a book that's just a book, okay?
是她小时候最喜欢的书   《天鹅绒兔宝宝》的珍本
It's an early edition of the Velveteen Rabbit. It was her favorite book as a kid.
如果她喜欢  告诉我  好吗
So, uh, just let me know if she likes it, okay?
没问题
You got it.
谢谢你  我欠你一次
Thanks man. Thanks for doing this. I owe you one.
给你的20块没有找钱  是吧
Oh, hey! There wasn't any change from that twenty, was there?
没有  不只20块呢
No, it came out to an even twenty.
哇  跟新书差不多贵
Wow. That's almost as much as a new book.
Jeepers Creepers
Where'd you get those peepers?
Jeepers Creepers Where'd you get those eyes?
还是没要到  对吧
You didn't get the money, did you?
也许我该在间断的时候去
Maybe I can try at intermission?
菲比  拜托  你知道  我们就走吧
Phoebe, come on... you know what? Let's just go!
不行  钱没拿到不能走
No! Hey, we're not leaving until we get paid!
我真不知道她把自己当谁了
I don't know who she thinks she is!
受够了
Enough is enough!
喂  寡妇
Okay, Widow!
寡妇  打扰一下  打扰一下
Widow? Excuse me? Excuse me!
谢了  显然这是你非常难过的时候
Thanks. Um, clearly this is a very, very hard time for you.
但我们提供了服务  就该得到报酬
Um, but we provided a service, and we deserve to be paid...
因为你们吃都吃了
...because you ate that service.
钱没付清之前  我们不会走的
and, um, we are not leaving here until we're paid every penny. ...
知道为什么吗  女士  我们只是临时承包  没别的地方可以去
'Cause you know what, lady? We're part time caterers, and we have no place else to go.
好  我去拿皮包
All right. I'll get my bag.
很好
Good.
我留下几张名片
I'm gonna leave some cards here.
下次有丧事需要请考虑我们
Please think of us for your next event.
你想进来吗
So you want to come inside?
想
Yes.
我想
Yes, I do.
我马上回来  你随便坐
I'll be right back. Make yourself comfortable.
猜猜我是谁
Guess who. Uh...
卫生稽查人员
Department of Sanitation?
是我
It's me. Ha, oh!
啊呜
Aw!
怎么了
What?
喔  雪柔   喔  罗斯
Oh, Cheryl! Oh, Ross!
啊
Oh! God!
啊呜   我的天啊
Aah! Oh, my God!
不  不
No! No!
等等  不  那是我的仓鼠  是蜜琪
Wait! No! No! It's my hamster! It's Mitzi!
天哪  对不起  雪柔  我吓到了
Oh my god! I'm so sorry, Cheryl. I must have freaked out.
哦  谢天谢地  幸好不是蜜琪
Oh, thank god, it's not Mitzi.
只是一只一般的老鼠
It's just a rat.
完成了
I did it! Aah!
我填完了  我一个人把它填完了
I finished it! I did it all by myself!
却没有人和我拥抱
And there's nobody to hug.
躲开
Move!
嘿  嘿  你们
Hey! Hey, you guys!
我一个人把字谜填完了  拥抱我
I finished the crossword all by myself! Hug me.
太棒了
Uh... yay!
恭喜  祝贺  谢谢你
Oh, that's great! Congratulations! Thank you!
宴会怎么样  太棒了
Hey, how'd the catering go? Oh, it was great!
那个寡妇不肯付钱  菲比就骂到她付钱为止
The widow wouldn't pay, so Phoebe yelled at her 'til she did.
没错  我是强硬派
Yeah. I'm a hard ass.
我是软弱派
And I'm a wuss.
我们应该联手
And we should be partners.
对啊  强硬加软弱  我们可以对抗犯罪
Yeah. Hard Ass and Wuss. We could fight crime!
等一下  菲比
Wait a minute, Phoebe.
我们是该联手
We should be partners.
我们应该成为承包商搭档
We should be catering partners.
我是说  你想嘛  你现在没工作  我们又合作无间
I mean, think about it! You're not working right now, and we have such a great time together!
好  我下厨  你管钱
Okay. I can cook and you can take care of the money.
我就像娶了一个五十年代很传统的老婆
Yeah. Oh! It'll be like I have a wife in the fifties!
嘿   嘿
Hey. Hey!
嗨  怎么样  她喜欢这个礼物么
Hey, how'd it go? How'd she like the gift?
哦  兄弟  她爱死这个了  她现在去给莫妮卡和瑞秋看呢
Oh, man, she loved it! She's over there showing Monica and Rachel right now.
是吗  太好了
Oh yeah? That's great!
嗨  听着  老实说
Hey, listen, I gotta tell ya,
把功劳都给我  我很过意不去
I feel kinda bad taking credit for this, because
我可有得爽了
man. am I gonna get a lot of credit for this!
嗨  嗨
Hey. Hey.
生日快乐
Hey. Happy birthday.
谢谢
Thank you.
你知道  钱德也有礼物要送你
You know, uh... Chandler got you a gift, too.
不  他没有
No, he didn't.
他有  看  看  就在桌子上  哈呵呵
Yeah, he did. Look, look, it's right there on the counter! Ha-ho-ho!
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你何必破费
You really didn't have to.
你以为这是一支笔  其实转过来还有时钟
See...You think it's just a pen, but you turn it over and it's also a clock.
好棒的礼物
Yeah. No, this is great.
谢谢你  钱德  不客气
Thank you, Chandler. Oh. Yeah.
啊  哦
Aw. Heh.
要睡觉了吗
Wanna go to bed?
我马上就来
I'll be in in a minute.
别忘了带猛男体验券
Oh, uh... Don't forget your coupon.
晚安
Good night.
谢谢你的礼物
Um, thank you for the gift.
我只是想有时你写字
Oh, uh, I just knew that sometimes when you're writing...
你...你有时候不知道确切时间
you... you don't always know the exact time.
不  我...我不是说笔  谢谢你那本书
No, I... I didn't mean the pen. Thank you for the book.
书
Uh, the book?
《天鹅绒兔宝宝》
The Velveteen Rabbit?
我觉得跟你有关
I kinda have the feeling you had something to do with it.
什么意思
What do you mean?
乔伊送我的时候说
Well, uh, when Joey gave it to me, he said,
"因为我知道你喜欢兔子  也喜欢起司"
"This is 'cause I know ya like Rabbits, and I know ya like cheese."
谢谢  我好喜欢
Thanks. I love it.
你一定花了不少功夫  这很不好找
And I know how hard it must have been for you to find.
如果你没听到  我的意思是"还好啦"
By the way, in case you missed that, that sound was, "Uhl, ell."
你一定很喜欢乔伊  才会这么费心
You must really like... Joey... to go to all that trouble for him.
是啊  他是…
Oh, yeah, he's my...
他是我最要好的朋友
He's my best friend.
好  晚安
Well. Good night.
那可是限时体验券
Hey, that coupon expires, you know.
你不认识我   我是莫妮卡.盖勒   罗斯的妹妹
Hi. Uh, you... you don't know me, I'm Monica Geller... Ross's sister.
哦  你知道  太糟糕了 我们分手了
Oh, yeah. Oh, you know, that's too bad that didn't work out.
对  总之  他跟我说了你家的情况
Yeah. Anyway, he told me about your apartment.
我听了后   想着就睡不着
And, um, I couldn't sleep, thinking about it.
你能让我打扫一下么
So, uh, would it be okay if I cleaned it?
不行吗
No?